DOAA SAAFAN

Dublin, Ohio

Email: <u>doaa_safan2000@yahoo.com</u>

Phone: 6149298196

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/doaa-saafan-32923b64/
Portfolio: https://doaasaafan.github.io/UX UI HW 19/

SUMMARY

UI/UX designer studied at Ohio State University UI/UX bootcamp program. Specializing in user research, usability testing, information architecture, wireframing, prototyping and interaction design, aim to create interfaces that are usable, enjoyable and accessible and that meet the needs of the user.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical:

Google Suite, Microsoft Office, Trello, Slack, Zoom

UX/UI:

User Research, Information Architecture, Storyboarding / User Journey Mapping, Wireframing, Responsive Design, Usability Testing, Iterative Design Thinking, User Interface Prototyping, Heuristic Evaluation Testing

Web:

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Adobe XD, Sketch, Figma, Miro

Programming:

C, C++, Java, Java Script, PHP, SQL, DB2, Python

PROJECTS

Peer to Peer Mobile Application | **Link to Project** [always write out link address] ● Design a mobile application for self storage which helps anyone to rent out spaces he needs from someone near him or list unused space for rent and increase his income.

• Used Figma and Google suite.

US Department of Interior Desktop Application | **Link to Project** [always write out link address] • Redesign the website of the US Department of Interior.

• Used Figma and Google suite.

Hope for children Desktop Application Link to Project [always write out link address] • Redesign the website of Hope for Children, a non profit charity website which collects donations to aid sexually and physically abused children.

• Used Figma and Google suite.

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer

The Ohio State University

May 2024- Sep 2024 Dublin,Ohio

Hope for Children

Redesign the website of Hope for Children, a non profit charity website which collect donations to aid sexually and physically abused children.

US Department of Interior

Redesigning the website and desktop application.

Peer to Peer

Create a self storage mobile application.

System Administrator and Administration Supervisor Raya Information Technology	2012 - 2015 Cairo/Egypt
Senior Customer Relation Administrator Raya Information Technology	2009 - 2012 Cairo/Egypt

EDUCATION

UI/UX Boot Camp: Ohio State of University, Ohio An intensive 24-week long boot camp

Application Development Boot Camp: Ministry of Communication and Information Technology, IBM, Egypt An intensive 9 months long boot camp

Certifications:

- UI/UX designer by OSU
- Certified Associate in Project Management by PMI
- Creative Problem Solving and Decision Making by Raya Academy
- Quality Management System by TUV
- IBM Certified Application Development with IBM WebSphere Studio by IBM
- IBM Certified Associate Developer WebSphere Studio by IBM
- IBM Certified Database Associate-DB2 Universal Database by IBM
- IBM Certified Solution Developer XML and Related Technologies by IBM
- Soft Skills by Dale Carnegie
- Communication Skills by Logic Management Consulting

Bachelor of Art English language and literature: Ain Shams University - cairo, Egypt